Hello everyone and welcome
back to English Pod, we have an
upper intermediate lesson for
you today, my name is Marco
And my name is Catherine, so
today we're talking about something
that everyone who's ever lived
away from home has felt before
Right, and that's the word we're going
to preview today. The word is homesick.
All right, so let's take a look at
that in today's language preview
vocabulary preview
All right, so homesick if you
feel homesick or you are homesick
Well, yeah, you you could say I'm homesick
right now, or are you feeling homesick?
So it's a word that means I
Missed my home. I miss my
family. I'm far away or I haven't
seen my family a long time and
for some reason you just feel sad
Okay, so it's a it's a
feeling you feel a little bit
depressed you feel sad
because you're homesick, right?
Okay, so this is what's
happening today in our
dialogue, so let's listen
to it for the first time
Oh
Tom, how are you? Hey, we missed
you at the party last night. Are you okay?
I don't know I didn't
really feel like going out.
I guess I'm feeling a
little homesick. Come on
We've been through this already look
I know the adjustment was
hard when you first got here,
but we agree that you're
going to try and deal with it
I was it's just that the
holidays are coming up
And I won't be able to go home
because I can't afford the airfare.
I'm just longing for some
of the comforts of home
Like my mom's cooking
and being around my family
Yeah, I can get pretty
lonely over the holidays
When I first got here,
I'd get depressed and
nostalgic for anything
that reminded me of home
I almost let it get to me,
but then I started going out
keeping myself busy and
before I knew it I was used to it
I see what you mean,
but I'm still bummed out
Okay, how does this sound? Let's get you
suited up and hit the dance club tonight
I hear that an awesome
DJ is playing and there
will be a lot of pretty
single girls there
You know, I could really go for that
You don't mind being
my wingman for tonight.
Not at all. It'll be fun. It
will be like a boy's night out
Well, kind of great. I
must warn you though.
Whatever happens. Don't
let me go on a drinking binge
Trust me. It's not a pretty picture
All righty, we're back.
So yeah, I guess he's very
homesick very homesick
and his friend is really worried
Yeah, but actually, I think
this is common right to be a
homesick during the holidays
like Christmas for example
Oh man, it's the worst during
the holidays because you think of
all the traditions and all the
things that you normally do at home
And you're not doing them.
Mm-hmm. So this is something
we're gonna talk more
about a little bit later on
But let's take a look at some of the
language that was used in language take away
Language takeaway
This first one is key, right?
So when you move away from home
or when you move to a new place
You have a period of adjustment
so adjustment is kind of
Finding the right balance
or doing something
so that you can kind
of feel comfortable
Okay, so you have to
adjust to your new life
life away from home
or your new environment
So many times people say wow
moving to China must be a big adjustment
So means there's so many
differences that it must take
a long time to feel
comfortable again. Okay.
All right So that's adjustment.
What else do we have?
Well, we've got this next
phrase that's it's really important
I think but often gets overlooked.
We say the comforts of home
Right comforts of home so comforts
pretty easy, right feeling comfortable
So you have comfort, but
the comforts are of home
are things that are
different with every person
But those are things that
you have at your home
or your childhood home
or your parents home
That make you feel
good and feel happy.
So they're not only physical
things or objects, right?
They can be like your
mom's cooking or maybe
even just spending
time with your family
Right or reading the newspaper
with your dad or things
that you're you're used to
that you don't have anymore
And so those are the comforts of home I
could say Mark go, do you miss the comforts
of home in Ecuador? I
mean do you have anything?
It's really of course of course
I think one of the main things
is actually not living in this city
because I used to live in the
Valley a little bit further away and
Kind of almost countryside so that's
one of the comforts of home that I miss. Oh
Making me nostalgic and
I never even been all right
Well, this is our next word
actually right nostalgic nostalgic
It's a feeling I'm feeling nostalgic
or he's just really nostalgic
And so to be nostalgic is to kind of
think about a time before or you know
Think positively about
something that you
experienced before so
it's not usually a bad thing
It's never bad thing. It's
right nostalgia is a good
warm fond memory of something
of something from your past
So you start thinking
of something from your
past that maybe brings
a nice warm feelings
Maybe a little bit sad
because you miss those times,
but it's usually thinking
about the past right?
So I have nostalgia for my childhood.
I loved you know summers in
Chicago when it was hot and
the kids would play in the sprinkler
And I have my dog and you know
it's a happy feeling right so nostalgia
would be the noun and nostalgia
would be the adjective exactly
All right, and our last word for
today on language takeaway is
Bumped out bummed out. I'm bummed out.
We've got another feeling here
So we're all full of
feelings today bummed out
is a sad feeling so to be
bummed is kind of slang
And it means to be sad.
Okay, or disappointed
the point so you you
come into the office Marco
And you look a little tired and say are you
okay? Are you bummed out about something?
Hmm, I can say yeah, I lost my wallet
last night, so I'm really bummed out
Oh, or something like
that. So yeah, you feel
bummed out when something
bad or sad happens, right?
All right, so why don't
we move on now to a
couple of different
phrases on fluency builder
Fluency builder
All right, this first one is something
that you often say to old friends or family
You know when your friends are someone
they go through periods of happiness
and sadness and so when
someone's going through a down
period again You say oh
we've been through this already
We've been through this
already or you know when you're
giving someone advice and
they never take your advice
You say listen, we've
been through this already.
You should know by now
that I and then you know
Whatever the advice so this
has happened before or we have
experienced this before or we
already solved this problem or situation
Right, you could imagine two
bank robbers who are growing over
their plan for the 10th time and
then the one says to the other
Hey, we've been
through this already.
You should know the plan by now exactly all
right So we've been through this already
They were talking about the
adjustments and everything
and then what other
phrase did they use well
The next couple of phrases
have to do with the friends
suggestions because she has a
lot of ideas to cheer her friend up
The depressed one and the first thing
she says is hey, let's hit the dance club
Okay, let's hit the dance club
or let's hit the dance floor tonight
All right, so hit in
this case doesn't mean
like hit doesn't mean
you're punching someone
Uh-huh, it means to
go to or to do all right,
so we can say let's go
to the dance club tonight
Let's hit the dance club exactly
and doesn't have to be a dance club
But let's hit that concert tonight.
Mm-hmm. They're gonna go there.
Okay, so you can hit
pretty much any place, right?
Exactly and that this is a very kind of
Spoken language, so you
wouldn't say this in your essays
But it's a good way to talk about
plans with friends. All right, and our next
word actually is kind of interesting
because it's very colloquial and it's a
wingman. I can be your wingman
tonight. So wingman you have
to think about wing meaning
side not like a bird's wing
So a wing-mead side and
a wingman is a guy who will
go with you to a bar or
a club to kind of help you
Find a date or a girl or someone to
talk to. Okay, so this person this wingman
Usually keeps your
company and helps you
decide maybe what girl
to talk to or maybe even
Introduces you to
someone right at a club or
at a restaurant or bar or
whatever and you know
The key is that people don't
like to go along to bars, right?
Because you feel sad and
then you're you look weird
cuz you're all alone And
the same is true for girls
And so if a guy wants to go a
bar and he sees two girls well
He has to have a friend to
talk to the other girl right?
So wingman also helps in that
sense he helps balance things.
All right, so there's a whole
science behind the wingman
Yeah, I'm sure if you look it up on Wikipedia
you'll find ten pages of information
All right, so Since they are going out
tonight, they said it could be boys night out
Okay, so this is another
phrase you hear all the time
especially among young people
boys night out and girls night out
And so you know sometimes
you spend a lot of time with
your husband or your wife
or your boyfriend or girlfriend
And you just want to have
some time with your friends right
and so you call this girls
night for me girls night out
You just go out you do girl things
guys night out you do other things
Okay, and so in this case girls
only or guys only boys night out
Is only guys exactly and
that's why this is funny because
it's the girl who says
hey, let's have boys night
out I'm not really All
right, great and well
He agreed to go out
and everything with but he
warned her about him
going on a drinking binge
Okay, and this is important
a lot of people who were
depressed or sad when
they drink they drink a lot
And so binge means to do
something in excess to do it too much
Okay, so a drinking binge would be drinking
alcohol in excess too much too much
So getting drunk right away
and it's not healthy and we do not
Right exactly very good. So some very
interesting phrases in this dialogue today
I think we should listen to it one
more time and we'll be right back
Tom how are you hey, we missed
you at the party last night are you okay?
I don't know I didn't
really feel like going out
I guess I'm feeling a
little homesick come on
We've been through this already look
I know the adjustment was
hard when you first got here
But we agree that you're
gonna try and deal with
it. I was it's just that the
holidays are coming up
And I won't be able to go home
because I can't afford the airfare
I'm just longing for some
of the comforts of home
like my mom's cooking
and being around my family
Yeah, I can get pretty
lonely over the holidays
When I first got here,
I'd get depressed and
nostalgic for anything
that reminded me of home
I almost let it get to
me, but then I started
going out keeping myself
busy and before I knew it
I was used to it. I see what you
mean, but I'm still bummed out
Okay, how does this sound let's get you
suited up and hit the dance club tonight
I hear that an awesome
DJ is playing and there
will be a lot of pretty
single girls there
You know, I could really
go for that you don't
mind being my wingman for
tonight not at all It'll be fun.
It will be like a boy's
night out. Well kind of great
I must warn you though.
Whatever happens. Don't let me go
on a drinking binge. Trust
me. It's not a pretty picture
All right, we're back. So
speaking of homesick and holidays.
Do you actually get very depressed
or homesick during Christmas?
I do Well, my family has a lot
of Christmas traditions that are
just really kind of wonderful
and we do them every single year
And so the first time I
spent Christmas away I was
I was living in Italy and
it was kind of similar
But then the second
time was when I was living
in China and China was
just not the same no oven
So no Christmas cookies and no
granny who, you know, pours vodka
and eats meatballs and like my
mom not running around the kids
You just you feel lonely and then
all of a sudden you get a phone
call and it's the entire family
and they're all together eating
Having an amazing Christmas
and they think it's gonna help
you feel less homesick, but it
makes you feel more homesick
So you definitely have
have nostalgia for those
days during the holidays,
but what about you?
I rarely get homesick, but yeah
sometimes during Christmas or New
Year's New Year's we usually have
more unique traditions in Ecuador
So it's very fun. The family gets together.
We dance. We eat so
But yeah, I've been away from home so
long that I rarely get homesick anymore
But it's great to go back and
spend time with the family so after
my visit to Ecuador
then I might get homesick
for a little while But
then it was a way. Yeah
Well, you guys should tell
us do you ever feel homesick
and if you do, what do
you feel homesick about?
What do you miss maybe mom's cooking
maybe family maybe the comforts of home?
Yes, we're curious to hear your answers.
We have website english pod dot com
You can of course
also leave us questions.
We're happy to answer those and
until next time everyone. Bye-bye